This is from Benaras.
It is authentic, from...
... Sri Ram's era.
What a lovely
market this is Gulbadan!
I have never seen
anything like this in my life.
This is the, Meena Bazaar'.
This tradition of
putting up the Meena Bazaar,...
was introduced by lt
takes place twice a month.
The daughters of the wealthy
decorate their shops with...
... goods, and the
customers are generally...
from the royal families,
of high esteem and status.
Barring the king and princes, no
other man can enter the market.
It often happens that many
princes come to buy things,...
... but are instead taken
up by the beautiful women.
I wish I was sold
off to prince Khurram.
See young lady, this is
made by special artisans.
Just see, how beautiful!
Seems so real and authentic
as if it is going to speak out.
I will present
this to prince Khurram.
Oh no, Prince Sahriyar! I
thought of the beautiful...
... peacock, but here
comes a crow instead!
Come on lets go. If he
sees you, it'll be difficult...
... to get rid of him. Come on.
Dear - Please come here princess!
Look at these nice jewels...
...of Chandan(coloured rare
stones). I also have anklets,...
...and armlets and
pair of rare bangles.
Look at this nine
stringed rare necklace.
The person who wears
this will have the whole...
...world swooning at her feet.
This,,King' of all necklaces
is saying that,if his destiny...
...makes him adorn the neck of
his beloved', the whole world...
... would become envious of him.
O God!
Your majesty, the prince, please
accept this from your maid.
That lady, who touched
this necklace, who was she?.
She is the daughter of
the prime minister, Asif Khan.
She's so beautiful, like
brilliant light, and so heavenly.
Please send this gift on
my behalf to Arjuman Banoo.
As you say, your majesty!
Prince Khurram, I have
specially chosen this for you.
Beautiful, the brilliant face,
the most melodious voice.
- Were you saying something?.
- I was praising it's beauty.
There are so many like these.
The shops are full of them.
Come with me,
I'll show you. Come!
Banoo, someone has
sent this gift for you.
I don't accept
gifts from strangers.
He wasn't a stranger,
he was Prince Khurram.
So, now you couldn't
be having any objection?.
- Please accept them now. - So,
what if he is prince Khurram?.
Who does he think I am?.
Well he must have liked you,
that's why he sent this gift.
- Take it back! - What!
I said take it back.
What does this
smile of yours indicate?.
A new flower is
going to bloom very soon!
What kind of a flower?.
The love story of prince
Khurram and Arjuman Banoo.
What is this you are saying?.
Empress Noorjehan's daughter,
Ladli Banno, is obsessed...
... with Prince Khurram.
- She may be obsessed. - So,
now what will happen?.
A war between Empress
Noorjehan, and Prince Khurram.
,Your beauty in real life,
is not seen in your painting'.
Prince Khurram, the Emperor
has sent a message as to...
... why you didn't
appear in the court today?.
-I hope you are not feeling
ill. -Of course not, I am fine.
, I was so carefree and
bereft of this pain of love'.
,Those where great days, when
I was not enamoured by anyone'
The master has asked, why
haven't you eaten anything...
... since the morning?.
O God! Banoo, l
hope all is well.
Well, I am feeling a
little good, and a little bad!
,She has touched my heart'
Your highness Ladli
Banoo has asked about you.
- Thank her for inquiring.
- Sir she has said...
Go from here, just go! I don't
know what's happened to everyone.
The one whose message l
am waiting for, hasn't come.
While others keep
on sending messages.
Your highness tell
a message from her.
O Gulbadan, it's you!
Please come, and sit down!
- How are you feeling?.
- I am fine!
- Tell me, what can I do?. -
Sir, it's our duty to serve.
Listen, that necklace,...
hands of that lady?.
- Yes, I did give
it to her. - Then what?.
She said that she doesn't
take gifts from strangers...
... and she returned it.
O no, this
shouldn't have happened.
However, the manner in which
she refused seemed to be more...
... of an acceptance, and that
too, with a heart full of love.
You are so nice Gulbadan.
I swear, I would have died
had you not said these words.
Just wait here! Just
wait here, my saviour!
Here, this is a pigeon for her.
I will be indebted to
you the rest of my life.
If you so desire, should l
reveal what is in your heart?.
Definitely! But,
praise me a little extra.
Your wish is my command.
- Banoo, may your
maid enter?. - No! No! No!
Alright. I came here
because the prince has sent me.
I'll go now.
Who is it?. Gulbadan,
just listen. Wait! Wait!
Well Banoo, why is your
behaviour so changed today?.
Well, it's nothing.
Just like that.
Come on.
Come and sit down.
What should I do for you?.
- What can you do Banoo?.
- So what brings you here?.
The royal prince's
condition is so pitiable, Banoo.
Why?.
From the time you have
returned his gift, his heart...
... is completely broken.
He is neither, eating,
drinking, talking, or smiling.
His condition is so pitiable.
If you think that I have
hurt him, then you go ask for...
... forgiveness, on my behalf.
No, I won't do that.
Why don't you
accept his second gift?.
He said that the first gift
was lifeless, so it didn't...
... say anything, but this
gift is full of life, and...
... if you refuse to accept it
then the poor thing will not...
... be able to bear it.
- I have not
understood you. - Just wait!
- A pigeon! - Yes, a pigeon!
Now, with your delicate hands
write a letter, and ask for...
... forgiveness.
This mute pigeon will
bring two hearts together.
Don't tell this to anyone.
You better warn your
eyes not to give you away.
- I'll not tell this to anyone.
- You are very naughty!
Please accept this!
'The charm that you have is
not there in your picture.'
'Your image was
captured in colors.'
'You could not be
captured in colors though.'
'The warmth of your breath,
the fragrance..
..'of your body
could not be captured.'
The charms in your movement are
not there in my poetry.'
'Where is the poetry of
motion in a lifeless beauty??'
'There is neither
the charm of accent..'
'.. nor the charm of dissent.'
'There is no trap of silky
hair on the road of the traveler.'
'There is nothing
in the world like you.'
'Please let me see
you just once more.'
Good work, Bahadur!
Today, messages are
coming again and again.
It seems that both of us are
really pining for each other.
, Respected prince, I do not
have much freedom to go about'.
, Please accept my helplessness!
Arjuman!'
Arjuman Banoo, if you only
understood how helpless I am too.
Bagh Bahadur, Tell her,
I am longing for her.
,Why are you so
in my life again??'
, I want to see you once more
if you have pity on me then...
... today evening, at the shore
of the river Jamuna, please...
... meet me in the Baradari'.
, My eyes will await
you impatiently. Khurram'.
O God!
'Let the flowers touch your
feet it will be your mercy.'
'Otherwise, not only me,
but they too will complain.'
'The flowers which you spread,
I will walk on them.'
'l fear if this will
be an insult of love.'
'Please have mercy on the
restless hopes of the heart.'
'lf you walk so slowly,
there will surely be Armageddon.'
'Shame stops me,
here, love pushes me here.'
What did I know that the
heart would be in such a state??'
'One shows shame to
strangers and not to close ones.'
'lf you show shame in front
of me, it will be a problem.'
Banoo, I am very fortunate
that you gave so much respect...
... to these flowers and
touched them to your eyes.
They were flowers
that is why I did this.
If in place of flowers, l
had placed myself there, then?.
I would have respectfully given
a place to you too, in my eyes.
O God!
You have given the answer
to the emotions of my heart...
... with your
delicate pulsating heart beats.
- I am grateful to you.
- Even, I am grateful.
- You must be tired, please
sit down! - No, it's very late.
I have to go.
I have been waiting for so
long. This meeting is so short.
How will I spend my
time waiting for you?.
How will I live
without you Banoo?.
How were you living
till now?. - fallen in love.
So, when did you fall in love?.
The very first time I saw you,
I was madly in love.
I am in love, but much more.
It is like a disease, and...
... only you can treat me.
Only you can treat me.
Then you too have the
same and I am helpless.
Helpless!
Yes, like you, I am helpless
too. Atleast he said what was...
... in his heart, but l
couldn't even say that.
Beautiful!
These tantalizing eyes and
endearing looks, which can...
... make an angel, pine for you.
So what can one say
about human beings!
Let me go now.
Before you go, atleast tell
me when will we meet again?.
Whenever you call me. -
Tomorrow is the Meena Bazaar...
... please come there.
If this is your command
I will definitely come.
Listen, may God be with you.
Ladli Banoo can that
the person you dream...
about day and night, he starts
to dream about some one else.
No, this cannot be. I
will not let this happen.
Respected mother.
What is the matter?. Why is my
darling daughter so perturbed.
Mother, just see
what Gulbadan is saying.
Arjuman Banoo has enchanted
prince Khurram with her love.
Prince Khurram and Arjuman,
what is this you are saying?.
I am telling you empress,
what I've seen with my own eyes.
I do not believe it.
You must have seen a dream.
If you want to see if
it is real or a dream...
... see it tomorrow with
your eyes, in the Meena Bazaar.
Arjuman banoo will be there
tomorrow, and Prince Khurram too.
I have all sorts of goods.
Please buy from me.
- Banoo, who are you
waiting for?. - For no one.
- It's you. -
Ladli Banoo, I am sorry.
Alright, I forgive you.
But where are you
going in such a great hurry?.
No where special, I was looking
around in the Meena Bazaar.
It's not interesting to go
about alone, come along with me.
Please come.
Welcome prince, welcome banoo,
this special thing is for you.
Sir, this is that scarf
which is meant for Laila.
This is that special type
of scarf which Majnu saw...
... Laila in and
was smitten by Laila.
Why don't you
buy it Ladli Banoo?.
May be you too will
become the legendary Laila.
May your words come true. Give
it to me, You see, I'll wear it.
I have flowers like the Juhi,
begum they are like stars.
The eyes are so angry and
there is a sword in the hands.
I am sure, you have
a fight with someone.
- You have taken so long to
come - I would have come earlier...
... but one cat crossed my way.
I had so many doubts in my
mind, desires and wishes, were...
... getting restless.
Please forgive me Banno.
I didn't ever dream that you
would be waiting so impatiently.
Prince, there are so many
desires which if I want...
... to hold back,
I cannot do so.
There are so many aspirations
which just stay within the heart.
God has made our love so strong
that she lives in my heart...
... and I live in her heart.
Take guard, it's my turn.
Well, I have saved myself.
- Really, now try to save
again. - Oh no, I have lost.
That is because you
were playing the wrong move.
What is the matter,
you never lose so easily.
I will one day take
revenge for this defeat.
You are more than welcome.
I have won in love but
even then I have lost...
... everything to you.
Emperor, do you remember
when you lost, at that time, l...
... had a small girl in my lap.
You had put your hand on her
head and promised, that you...
... would marry your
dearest son with her.
Well, what do you want to say?.
I want to ask you, who is
is the most dearest person...
... in your life to you.
Every son is dear to his father.
But Khurram is full of
bravery and sagacity and so...
... he is the most dear to me.
What a happy event will it
be in our lives if Khurram...
... and Ladli Banoo
are married to each other.
Your idea is very good.
But before I take any decision,
it is important...
... that I find out the
feelings of Khurram too.
If Khurram
thinks differently....
Maybe my commitment to justice
would make me break my promise.
Emperor!
I am not only the father of
Khurram but an emperor, and...
... without giving this a
thought I cannot afford to...
... give my permission which
may not do justice, and might...
... be a blot on my ability.
My royal prince,
please accept my greetings.
,Today at the same courtyard
after sunset, I'll wait for you'
,Yours Arjuman'.
Be alert and stand
respectfully, the empress...
... Noorjehan is arriving.
Empress, I am surprised to
see a lady of your eminence...
... come to my humble home.
Please sit down.
What brings you here?.
Empress Noorjehan has not
come to the home of the prime...
... minister, Asif Khan, but
a sister has come to the home...
... of her dear brother.
My eyes are so delighted and
my heart so full of happiness.
I see the Empress Noorjehan
everyday, but I am meeting...
... my sister
Mehrunissa after so many years.
There is so much difference
between the two of them.
Wearing the crown does change
ones outlook, but the heart...
... never changes.
May god let these feelings
always nurture inside you.
- Where is my beautiful doll,
Arjuman?. - I'll just call her.
Please accept the greetings
of your subject, empress.
May god bless you.
Come and sit near me.
She has really grown up.
Have you thought about...
... her future brother?.
Where do I have the time?.
she would have....
So what if she doesn't have
a mother, I am always there...
... to think about my doll.
From today, she will stay
in my palace and I will look...
My daughter is very fortunate.
big worry of mine.
I will never forget
this favour. - lts my duty.
Get ready, you will
have to come with me.
You are fortunate that you'll
get a mother's love once again.
She has promised
to come after sunset.
Sun, for Gods's sake,
why don't you go down?.
What is this nonsense?.
What do you mean by this?.
'You will have to
keep your promise.'
'Whether the world or
God himself stops you.'
'You will have to come,
O beloved.'
'The thirsty eyes have called;
the roads of love have called.'
'O the life of
coyness and life and charm.'
Don't trouble me,
you will have to come.'
'l accept that I will
have to leave this world..'
..'Understand this,
whenever you..'
'.. remember me, l
will have to come.'
'l will not take
accusations on my loyalty.'
'l have given you my heart.
I'll give you my life too.'
'When we have dealt with love,
how can we be scared??'
'The promise that I have made,
I will have to keep it.'
'l will have to come.'
'Till the time the
moon and the stars shine..
..'the promises of our
love will not be broken.'
'We will have to become
crazy for each other and come.'
Why did you take so
long to come Banoo?.
Will this tradition of love
never change, for those in love.
While I long to meet you.
You love to make me wait.
This is not so prince. A
wall has been built in...
... our path of love.
A wall! Who has
tried to do this?.
That I don't know. Today the
Empress suddenly came and took...
... me to her
palace as her guest.
Then what happened?.
As I was about to come, I found
myself surrounded by the guards.
That means that our
love is no longer a secret.
The empress has got
the news of our meetings.
So why did she put
the guards to surround me?.
Besides her who has
the courage to do this.
She is the only one who can
treat the daughter of the...
...the prime minister like this
and even try to put a guard...
and keep a watch, on the heir
of the empire, prince Khurram.
But why has she done this?. What
enmity does she have with me?.
Her enmity is not with
you Banno, but it is with me.
Why?.
She wants Ladli
Banno empress of lndia.
But this plan of
hers will never succeed.
It is not easy to challenge
her, prince. I am scared that...
... she might separate us
forever, from each other.
I take an oath on that sacred
honour which lovers stand by.
Banoo, we will keep meeting,
in this place and, will...
... continue meeting so.
Prince!
Let's forget our
pain and beautiful...
... night, let us smile together
with the stars shining up there.
This shining moon.
This beautiful garden and the
shore of the river Jamuna,...
what a glorious view is this!
What a beautiful place is this.
Prince, if I die then
make my tomb in this place.
Don't say this, Banoo.
I'll get such a magnificent
palace made here, which will...
... be
incomparable in the world.
Yes, it should be made of
marble like a beautiful flower.
In which the fragrance
of our love will be spread.
Which, in such a moonlit night,
will shine like our love.
It will show the moon in the sky,
the reflection of its beauty.
Prince Khurram, you will
make such a palace, won't you?.
Banoo, I have already made
it's foundation in my heart.
The picture of that palace is
already taking shape in my heart.
One day, I will take the
dream out of my heart and...
... make it stand near
the shore of the Jamuna.
Then the whole world will
shine with the light and...
... glory of our love.
- Prince. - Banoo.
Thank god so much, for
having saved my esteem.
Empress!
The path you are going
on has only thorns in it.
I do not understand, empress.
Do not try to hide anything.
I have seen everything with...
... my own eyes
in the Meena Bazaar.
Right now where are you
coming from, I know this too.
Do not go so far ahead on
this road of love, so that...
... it is
difficult for you to return.
Those who tread this path
do not come back, Empress.
You impudent girl! Do
not forget what you are!
I can give you everything
for getting out of my way.
What can you give me empress?.
Instead, you are asking me!
I know Arjuman,
empress of lndia.
What will I do
becoming the empress of lndia?.
I Apologize, The empress of lndia,
right now, is herself standing...
...in front of an ordinary
girl asking her for something.
You have seen my kindness.
You have not seen how hard...
... and vicious I can be.
The love that you are so
proud of, I can crush him under...
... my feet and destroy him.
Empress, history is witness
to the fact that regimes have...
... given in to legends of
love, while love has never...
... Iost or bowed
down in front of regimes.
Quiet! I give you a last chance.
Get out of my way, and for...
... this I am ready
to give you anything.
Besides Khurram, I can get
you married to any other prince.
I can give you
land and any district.
Tell me what you want?.
This same question, had
once come in front of you too.
When you loved Prince Salim,
this was the same question...
... which the Emperor
Akbar had put to you.
Tell me empress, which land
did you ask for, and which...
... district did you want?.
Except for Salim, which
prince did you pine for?.
Arjuman, you are
going beyond limits.
Your obsession for becoming
the empress of lndia, has even...
... made you forget yourself.
No, it's the Empress, who
has forgotten herself, when...
... she became Noorjehan.
She has forgotten Mehrunissa!
I request you to decide
about me and the prince,...
... as Mehrunissa would have,
and not as empress Noorjehan.
Do not treat me in had treated
you by emporor Akaber..
Emperor had done what he
had to, and I too will do...
... what I have to do.
Remember Arjuman,...
possible for my daughter.
Even I am your daughter. I
am your brother's daughter.
Every daughter is
the empresses' daughter.
Do not sacrifice one
daughter for another.
So you refuse completely.
May be, you are not aware...
... of the consequences.
People who love, never think
about the consequences, empress.
You are great.
Why is there so much laughter
and joy in Mumtaz Mahal's Palace?.
To celebrate her birthday,...
organised a gathering...
... of eminent poets. - Good.
Prince Khurram will
be the special invitee.
- What about prince Shariyar?. -
If you wish, we can invite him.
But your presence
emperor, is very important.
Ladli Banoo has specially
made this request to you.
I will definitely
attend the symposium.
Let the symposium begin.
'When they remove the
veil from their face.'
'They take away the color
of the garden of flowers.'
'Wine cellars are
existent in their eyes.'
'They make crazy,
whoever they see.'
'They answer
loyalty with betrayal.'
'How heartless they are, what
they take and what they give.'
'They are sitting as if
they have seen us at all.'
'This is the charm
that makes us crazy.'
'They decorate youth with
different clothes of beauty.'
'That's how the one who
respect beauty answer it.'
'What is love?., ask the kings.'
'They make beauty
sit on the throne.'
'O the people who
count money with money.'
'We answer love with love.'
Who is this ill mannered
person?. Maids, go and see.
But the verse of
the poem is very good.
Young lady, come forward.
The emperor has heard your
beautiful poem but has not...
... seen your face.
Who are you?.
I am your subject,
Arjuman Banoo.
Daughter of Asif Khan, and the
granddaughter of Mirza Qayat.
How beautiful!
She is a beautiful jewel.
I had thought that I had...
... acquired the
most enchanting pearl.
But even now, there are
such priceless jewels present.
Arjuman, by reciting this poem
you have made me interested in...
... poetry, go beyond extremes.
I want to hear the whole poem.
As you say your highness.
'We are punished
for the crime of love.'
'They are so stupid,
they fan fire.'
'People call us crazy
and are loyal to us.'
'Whether we live or not,
we keep our promises.'
'What is a throne
and what is wealth?. '
'The lovers give
up God's name too.'
'We have given the heart,
and taken the asset of loyalty.'
'You can happily give me
any punishment you wish.'
Beautiful, what words, it is
full of truth and philosophy...
.... and indeed
a beautiful verse.
By God, this is magic!
It is magic!
Beautiful, what words!
What a great meaning they have!
As if flowers are
gently dropping from her words.
Supreme God, you give
support to those who have no one.
You are the protector
those who are helpless.
A sinner like me, my
respect is in your hands.
Please give me courage, that
even if I have to face death l...
... can look into
its eyes and smile.
That I can face all the
adversity and difficulties.
- Asif Khan is alive,
my daughter. - Father!
A friend told me that
your life is in danger.
I did not believe him.
After coming here, it proved
to be right. Come along with me.
Father, I am scared that...
have to face danger.
The empress might do something.
The empress can take
away my status and respect.
But she cannot take
away my child from me.
So much resentment, and so
much anger, and that too...
... without any reason.
Without any reason!
Empress, can I ask, why
is my daughter under a siege.
Under the pretense of love
and you exposed your enmity.
Dear brother, if a young
girl goes on the wrong path,...
... and her feet begin to falter
and if she leaves the right...
... path, starts to venture
on the dark road, then, to...
... put her under
siege is not a sin.
You are insulting me, if
anyone else would have put...
... this serious allegation,
then I promise on God l.....
Behave in a decent manner,
Asif Khan. Do not forget that...
... you are a talking
to the Empress Noorjehan.
You too, do not forget that
you have put a slap on the...
... face of Amir-Ul-Umrahi,
Amin-U-Daulla, the prime...
... minister, Asif Khan.
The consequence will
not be right, Mehrunissa!
Consequence of what?.
Young man, when the fragrance
of flowers begins to emerge...
... from the gardens then
it is under stood that the...
... flowers have opened up.
In the same way, when a
father sees a special kind...
... of sparkle in the
eyes of their children they...
... realize that their
children have grown up.
They start making
arrangements for their wedding.
The Empress has given a
suggestion, which I think...
... is agreeable to me.
I think that the proposal
of Ladli Banoo for marriage...
.... to you, is right.
Emperor, if you don't
mind may I say something.
Of course you can,
I want your opinion.
Emperor when you saw that
special sparkle in your son's...
... eyes, then you must have
noticed this too, from where...
... did that sparkle come from.
Which star broke from
the sky and entered my eyes.
Khurram, last night in the
symposium, I saw a little...
... unpleasant behaviour.
Which indicated the and
uncontrolled behaviour.
For which an Emperor
can give of punishment.
If a loving father
forgives his favourite son.
Forgive me for entering
at this delicate moment.
What is the discussion taking
place between father and son?.
Khurram, you can go now.
I have kept your
proposal in front of him.
If he had agreed to marry
Ladli Banoo, I would have...
... been extremely happy.
But I think he is in love. I
fear, that if he is forced...
too much, then the love within
him, will turn into revolt.
I do not want, that
Mughal history repeats once...
... again the story of
emperor Akbar and Prince Salim.
Please do not worry at all.
Some solution to this problem...
... will be found.
Khurram has not accepted
just Ladli Banoo, but has...
... Iost the crown
and throne of lndia too.
Sir, the name of
that prescription is...
..., Ustai lshq Afroz'
- It is a very strange name.
- Not only the name but it...
.... does also strange things.
You just have a pinch of
this in the betel leaf,...
and Ladli Banoo will
start pining for you.
Then the second time you have
it, she'll leave the house...
... dying to come to you.
As you are having it
for the third time...
... Ladli Banoo's
arms will be around you.
Beautiful! What a
beautiful thought!
Mirza, this is the medicine
that my aching heart needs.
- Prepare this potion at once.
- Sir, I'll just prepare it.
Sir, I need two pearls should...
... be given to me sir.
Kwaja Masroor - yes sir.
Khwaja Dalbir my special
assistant had once tried to make...
a fool of me, and I had
got him whipped hundred times.
Now how is he feeling?.
Sir he could only tolerate fifty
whips, and after that he died.
May God have mercy on him.
Sir what is the need of
any gold of iron will do.
Not that iron, but this
iron will be used on him.
Just give me your
permission,... Banoo and make...
her the queen of your heart
or else my name, Khaza Masroor...
... will never be heard again.
Just give me your
permission and I will bring her.
Everyone stand and be alert
Empress Noorjehan is coming.
Why did you take the trouble?.
You should have sent for...
... a small person
like me. I would have come.
Sometimes one's
destiny comes itself.
- Your fortunes are on the rise.
- I do not understand Empress.
Change your lifestyle and
take interest in the matters of...
... the kingdom, and
try to please the Emperor.
Your command, Empress.
I will definitely obey.
But why should I do all this?.
Because I like
you with all my heart.
I want to hand over to you
the dearest flower of my life.
But in order to get that flower
Shariyar, you will have to...
... become so great, that
if that flower is offered to...
you in marriage, she must not
think that her esteem is lowered.
I just need your blessings.
I will even pluck the stars...
... from the sky and bring them.
Very good.
If you show the same
commitment in your character,...
then that day is not far away
when your hands can reach for...
... the throne of lndia.
What are you saying,empress?.
Is this possible?.
A person is the
creator of his own destiny.
There is very bad
news from Deccan.
What has happened there?.
Revolt has started
in the entire Deccan.
The kings of Bijapur,
Daulatabad and Ahmednagar...
... have announced
revolt against the Dil-E-Elahi.
They will be stopped.
Asif Khan, call the ministers
and Amirs for discussions.
If we do not crush the
courage and revolt of the kings...
...of the provinces of Deccan
then it will mean that our...
... Mughal reign is in danger.
In order to crush the
rising heads of these snakes,...
... I myself will go there.
We all agree with the
decision of the emperor.
Emporor, I feel that it is not
right for you to go and crush...
... the rebels, yourself.
This will show our weakness.
My advice is to send
someone else on this mission.
I appreciate the
empresses' advice.
But I know that the rebels of
the Deccan have many times...
offered a tough resistance
to some of our bravest...
and valiant warriors
like prince Pervai,...
Khan-E-Khana, Man
Singh and Khan-E-Alam.
Which brave warrior do we
have who can take on the burden...
... of this dangerous encounter?.
- There is one person.
- Who is he?.
Prince Khurram.
Excellent. You've had mercy on
me whenever I've been in trouble.
The Emperor has full
acceptance of your decision,
Go quickly and...
Arjuman Banoo, if you
look at the sky and walk you...
...are bound to stumble.
Ladli Banoo, how come
you have lost your way?.
I have not lost my way but
have come to show you the way.
Because of your stupidness,
prince Khurram has taken the...
... first step towards his ruin.
What step?. What destruction?.
What has happened to the prince?.
Shehanshah Alam has
sent him to Deccan.
Not into the flames of war,
but into the flames of death.
This decision is not of the
Emperor but of the Empress.
I will not let the prince go. I
will not let him go at any cost.
Where are you going?.
Maybe you will not be able to
meet the prince, as he has...
... already left for Deccan.
No, he cannot go without
meeting me, he can never go.
Who are you?.
I am the personal
servant of Prince Khurram.
- Where is the prince?.
- He has left for Deccan.
He has left a message that
he would have definitely met...
you before going, but was
afraid, that love may become an...
... obstruction in his duty.
He asked you not to feel
any remorse, but pray that...
... he is
successful in his mission.
'O God, why is there war just
for land's sake on your Earth??'
'Why does everyone just
have the mind for violence??'
'The land is yours,
we are yours too.'
'Where does the
question of ownership come??'
'Why is there a
tradition of war??'
'What is this penchant
for killing and blood shed??'
'The people who
wish the world..'
'..Why are their
hearts so stingy??'
'Please give the
poor mothers and..'
'..dignified sisters a
life of peace and tranquility.'
'Those whom you
have given the power..'
'..give them the
light of mercy too.'
'Why do people have
so much arrogance??'
'Why is there rust on
the glass of the hearts??'
'O people who are
going for destruction.'
'Please give way
for armors to arrive.'
'May the gardens of
hearts not wither.'
'Please give asylum to love.'
'Why is there a celebration
of arrows instead of love??'
- Queen, queen. - Yes Emperor.
Your advice was so correct.
You words were so auspicious.
- I have good news from Deccan.
- May god make the emperor's...
... fortunes more bright.
After one and a half years my
Khurram return from Deccan.
The vanquisher of
Deccan my Khurram, my Khurram.
You have achieved that great
victory which has brought glory...
... and
magnificence to my reign.
The emperor is so pleased
with your victory that you will...
... be given that throne and
crown which till today has...
... not been given to any
prince of the Mughal rule.
There can never be two
swords in one sheath, and...
... nor can there be two
thrones in the same court.
From today there will be two
thrones in the court of Jehangir.
Come with me.
The light of my eyes.
This throne is yours.
This is the
greatness of the Emperor.
Sit down.
The great achievement of
prince Khurram should be written...
... with golden
letters in the Mughal history.
This also must be written that
the emperor was so happy with...
... the achievement of his son
Khurram, that he gave him the...
... title of Shahjehan.
Hail Khurram alias Shah Jahan!
Prime minister Asif Khan, to
honour my son, please organize...
... a magnificent gathering.
Your command will be
carried out, Emperor.
Prince Khurram, and now
the emperor Shahjehan,...
... please accept the
greetings of your subject.
Tell me, Did you ever remember me
there?. - Why did you ask this?.
I heard - What heard.
I have heard that the women
of Deccan are very beautiful.
You are right. Just in time,
I was saved from embarrassment.
Why?.
Don't ask me this Banno.
When I captured a city,...
... many gifts were given to me.
The one who presented
the gifts was a young lady.
- A young lady! - Yes.
She looked like, lightening
which had dropped from the sky.
- I was totally
smitten by her. - Why?.
Because she was so beautiful.
- Then?. - She came
smiling towards me.
Then she went away. I
had lost my heart to her.
I followed her and called
out to her and she stopped.
Then?.
Then her helpless eyes
looked at me and the...
... whole universe lighted up.
I moved forward,
she too moved forward.
Our hearts started to beat.
Overwhelming emotions of love...
... were felt in my heart.
I moved my hand forward,
she too gave me her hand.
My lips were trembling, and
her lips too started to tremble.
Then I said something to her,
that she got up and went away.
I am very happy,
you deserve this.
But I went after her again.
I asked her name.
- Do you want to know her name?.
- I don't want to know.
Listen to me, you are crying.
Her name was Arjuman Banoo.
- Really! - She was
no one else, it was you.
It was your memory.
It was your dream.
Unneccassarily you troubled me.
'The youth makes
the life beautiful.'
'Love gives proof
that the heart exists.'
'lf this is not here,
there is nothing in life.'
'ln every heart,
there exists a veiled one.'
'The oscitations of beauty
exists in every celebration.'
'The shadow of love
exists everywhere.'
'Transparent somewhere
and prevalent somewhere.'
'The rhythm of love
is existent on this.'
'The moonlight is
existent on this.'
'lf you wish, take
heaven here itself.'
Take care.
O Lord! I will have to go.
As soon as the prince came,
I caught hold of him and...
... threw him on the floor
so badly that the body of...
... the prince fell on the
floor and his soul went up there.
Very good. I am very happy
the achievement you have made...
... will be written in
history in golden letters.
Now, I can see the royal
throne right in front of me.
- Listen. - Yes sir.
Where did you
bury the dead body?.
This work we left for
Khawaja Mashroof to do.
He will definitely do
something about the body.
Sir, there has been a disaster.
What has happened?.
The body of prince
Khurram has disappeared.
Where has it gone
and how did this happen?.
God only knows this.
You fools, if god knows
everything then what...
... do you all know?.
Why did you all
leave the body there?.
Remember if the emperor finds
out about this conspiracy,...
... he'll break my bones.
Queen, practically all the
princes and princesses have...
... come to see me, but
I haven't seen Khurram.
Is he not aware of my illness?.
How can this be,
emperor?. In front of the whole...
... gathering, you fell sick
how is it that he didn't see you.
Then why has he not come?.
Maybe he is busy in
some other interest of his.
He is young and has just
won laurels at the war and...
... the arrogance of the
honours you have bestowed on...
him is there too, so why should
he think of his sick father.
No queen, my
Khurram is not like this.
He should be informed immediately
that I'm restless to see him.
He has gone to sleep.
- How are you
feeling now?. - I am better.
- Should I put some ointment?.
- My saviour what is the...
... need of the ointment now.
When you put your hand on
my wounds, I was alright.
God is great, he saved you.
Or else the enemies were...
... out to see you killed.
I will go to the emperor just
now and tell him everything,...
... about this incident.
Don't go Arjuman, do not go.
This is the conspiracy of
the empress. Her magic is...
...going on, otherwise Shariyar
would have never got this...
... conspiracy in his head to
send me a letter on your behalf.
Let this be Arjuman. I will
give them such a befitting reply...
... that they'll
remember it forever.
This continuous absence
of a suspicion in my mind.
You are only suspicious, but
I am sure that he is involved...
... in some planning.
Shariyar send him a message that
by tomorrow evening Khurram...
... should give me the answer
for this behaviour of his.
Or else I will.....
- Banoo, some calamity has
happened. - What has happened?.
Prince Khurram has
been termed as a rebel.
The Emperor has ordered
that if the prince does not...
... go to see him, he
will be declared a traitor.
Me, and traitor. This is
the second trip of enemy.
- I have to go to him.
- How will you go?.
Those who have advised emperor
to order this they must have...
... made arrangements that
you should never reach him.
Whatever it is Arjuman.
The emperor will have to be told
who is the real traitor, even...
... if I have to put my
life at stake for this.
Prince, your life does
not belong to you alone.
I too have a right on it.
The empress has a lot
of pride in her kingdom.
She has forgotten that l
too belong to the same family.
In my blood too,
flows the same blood.
I too can give an
answer to all her conspiracies.
You do not worry.
I will find a way
out to meet the emperor.
You will definitely meet him.
Emperor has made
tomorrow Khurram does...
... meet him by tomorrow evening
he will be declared a rebel...
... and a traitor.
If he is alive, then
he will definitely try...
... to meet the emperor.
If Khurram reaches
there then we are dead.
This is very bad news prince
Shariyar, now what should we do.
Just think, think that if
Khurram is alive then why...
... is he alive and if he
is alive then where is he?.
Ask this from me?.
Gulbadan, what do you know?.
Arjuman begum has
given him love and shelter.
Right now, he is in the palace
of the prime minister Asif Khan.
Thank Gulbadan for giving
me this piece of news I will...
... give you
the greatest reward.
This is my promise. Now go.
Kwaja Masroor - Yes Sir.
The basement in which Khurram
is hiding, make that basement...
... into his tomb.
Outside the palaces of
Asif Khan and Jehangir,...
put security guards
at every step and corner.
See that Khurram does not
leave this place to go...
... to that palace.
Stop there.
You girls. Come on.
Where are you going with
wearing your anklets, making...
... all this sound.
You don't heard, Rana Daljit Singh
has become the father of a son.
They have sent sweets
for the empress Noorjehan.
What about giving us some too?.
Just look at this fool's face.
Give him to eat some,
or else he'll curse.
O God, but what wrong
have the other guards done?.
So lets give to all of them.
I have got the
announcement made.
It's already evening, but
Khurram hasn't still come.
Your servant is present.
Who is he?. Finish him off.
What is this condition
of yours?. Where were you?.
Forgive me but...
Please leave all of you.
Where were you till now?.
Why did you not come to see me?.
See this deap wound, emperor.
In your presence, in the
premises of the palace, an...
... attempt was made to kill me.
Who were those traitors who have
not attacked prince Khurram...
... but have
attacked Emperor Jehangir.
Tell me their names.
Father please be careful. Tell
me the names of those traitors.
Father, I can
sacrifice many lives for you.
Please do not get
agitated it'll effect your health.
- Khurram, I want their names.
- Names! I don't know, it was...
dark, I couldn't see anything.
You couldn't recognize them,...
because of my condition.
Come on tell me.
My Khurram is a
brave this I am aware of.
But today I have come to know
that he is a merciful human...
... being too, who out of
pity for his old father...
... is ready to hide the
names of his enemies too.
I am very pleased with you.
Father, in this happy atmosphere
I want to pay back the favour...
to that lady who put her youth,
her respect, her dignity...
... at stake and saved my life.
Who is she?.
The daughter of the prime
minister, she is Arjuman Banoo.
Not only you Khurram but the
whole Mughal empire is grateful...
to Arjuman Banoo, that she
has saved the most outstanding...
... Iight of this
dynasty from fading away.
Now very soon, I will get
you married to Arjuman Banoo.
I will with my own hands put
your wedding head gear on you.
The emperor has taken the
decision that Arjuman Banoo will..
marry prince Khurram and I too
have taken a decision that you...
... will marry Ladli Banoo.
I promise you that after I am
gone the empress of lndia will...
... not be Arjuman Banoo.
'The body of silver
and the eyes of gold.'
'To that add charms,
what can one say??'
'Who all has your beauty
destroyed, what can be said??'
'A sinful tongue,
and a sinful glance.'
'What can be said of
this color of your mind??'
'ls there such a love in
this world, what can one say??'
'Under the veil,
this face which as pink as a rose'
There is the color of the roses
as well as the shine of the stars.
'At this time, we don't care even
for heaven. What can one say??'
'Since the time I met you,
we have left the three worlds.'
'Leaving one need, all
our needs have disappeared.'
'We drank from
your beautiful eyes.'
'We even left
the glass of wine.'
'When the silky hair fluttered,
even we fluttered a bit.'
'We even forgot who
gets the world any longer.'
'Don't look at us
with such warm eyes..
'..these bodies can melt too.'
'Look in such a way, the dew
of beauty doesn't get evaporated.'
You forget the
beauty you have seen.
'What can be said of the
bestiality of you people??'
That you can win over us, do not
remain under that impression.
That we will disgrace ourselves,
we aren't so naive.
What if someone dies. Doesn't
mean an obligation on us.
Why should we talk to
someone whom we do not know.
Even if you desire,
we do not desire.
We do not desire,
we do not desire!
The people whom you refuse for,
what luck they have.
And those for whom you wish, their
fortune cannot be explained!
They give yearnings day and night.
This is the state of the lovelorns.
This is the state of the lovers.
Wherever they see a new face,
their heart goes a flutter.
They will take that. This is
the state of the lovers.
For whom we tolerate tortures
and hope, our fate is such
We are called crazy
by those same people.
This life becomes problematic
because of these lovers.
Should we look after them, or
should we take care of ourselves?.
Every word is a request,
every look is a question.
He's felling restless and sorrow.
My sleep has gone,
my peace has gone.
My previous 'taano
tavan ' has gone.
If this is the state of things,
I will soon lose my life.
If a person has a penchant to
commit suicide, what can one do?.
Someone cures person with
the potion of heart.
If someone flirts meaninglessly
why should one care?.
Why should one confess
the helplessness of love?.
It is enjoyable when you have
mercy and some one looks at you.
If I die, and people
accuse you of murder.
They don't die and
they don't live too.
What can be said
of these lovers?.
Both the
princes are married now.
I want to appoint both of
them heads of separate regions.
So that they can help
me in ruling the kingdom.
Emperor, my opinion is to
let Shariyar be in Agra...
... and let Khurram be sent
to Deccan as the incharge there.
This way the burden on you
will lessen, and the rebels...
... will never have the courage
to raise their heads against us.
What an idea! Empress,
you always kill two birds...
... with one stone.
I will, tomorrow itself,
give the order for his departure.
Its been ages since I have
been married, but my destiny...
... has not changed.
Lord, do not
disappoint me this time.
Let my wishes be fulfilled. Let
one flower bloom in my garden.
Give me one male child.
May your wish come true.
What's the news?. Is it a boy?.
No, it's a girl.
Give me my reward.
Oh no, again my
destiny has cheated me.
Why did you come here with
your stupid face, why didn't...
... you go to Burhanpur,
to Shahjehan.
Sir, do not get angry with her.
This is a gift of God.
Who wants such gifts?.
This is the third princess.
On the other hand Shahjehan
has no shortage of boys.
But here always girls born.
Sir, the angels have made
a mistake, they must have...
... exchanged the
children by mistake.
Otherwise, you would have
got a boy and he, a girl.
No, its not that Mirza.
It is in my destiny to be
defeated by Shahjehan in every...
... avenue of life.
What all didn't I try to do
against him, and what all...
didn't I do to take his life,
but nothing happened to him.
Empress, sent him thousands
of miles away from Agra to...
... Burhanapur, but my
destiny still evaded me.
Destiny has been very kind to
me. God has given me everything.
The biggest gifts are these
two smiling flowers in my life.
- There is one desire
still left. - A desire?.
My eyes are desperately
wanting to see Agra again.
That shore of the Yamuna.
That courtyard, where we gave...
... each other
our promises of love.
Do not worry begum, God is kind.
I am just waiting for some
news from the emperor's court.
If I am successful in this
campaign then I will ask...
... my father to let
me stay in Agra forever.
I want that during my life
time, the decision for my...
... succession takes place
so that after I am no more,...
... my sons do not fight
over the throne and crown.
I want to take this
decision with all of you.
If you want my humble opinion
then sir, I would suggest that...
... prince Khurram instead of
being sent to Kandhar, should...
... be called to
Agra immediately.
Seeing his capabilities in life,
its better that at this delicate...
... time he should
remain close to the Emperor.
Instead of him, prince Shariyar
should be sent to Kandhar.
You have said, what
my heart wanted too.
This is a very good suggestion,
Emperor.
Prime minister, immediately send
a messenger to Kandhar and ask...
... Khurram to
come back to Agra.
Your order will be carried out.
- I too wanted to say
something. - Empress, its you.
It is not my purpose to
disagree with the decision...
... of Emperor, nor do l
want to become an obstacle...
... in anyone's plans.
But to think
about It is my right,...
... and duty too.
You are right, Empress.
You can say what you want to.
Asif Khan is my brother.
I am not his enemy.
Today in his suggestion,
there was a selfish motive.
Empress! What is
this you are saying?.
Emperor, you know this very well
that Shariyar is not at all...
... familiar with the region of
Kandhar, and if he is sent to...
far away Kandhar, do you know
what its consequences will be?.
I will tell you today. Our
forces will be defeated.
The region of Kandhar
will be taken away from us.
While Shariyar will be killed.
This is what Asif Khan wants.
Supreme god, what should I do?.
My mental tension is increasing.
Continuing illness has taken
away my power of decision making.
Loyal people like Asif Khan
will turn so selfish with time,...
... this I had no knowledge.
Empress, You are not only the
empress of lndia but an empress...
... of wisdom and sagacity too.
I hand over the running
of the kingdom to you and...
... make an announcement
that from today all the royal...
... decisions have your
stamp of authority too.
Go immediately to Burhanpur
and give prince Khurram my...
...message, before destiny plays
another trick. He reached Agra.
The first order that I give
after taking over the reins is,...
... that Asif Khan be removed
from his post, and have no powers.
He should be put under guard.
He should not be allowed to
go out of the city of Agra.
- A disaster has taken place.
- What has happened?.
Empress has
stopped all your plans.
Emperor has handed over the
rule of the kingdom to her.
The first order she has passed...
Ionger the prime minister..
... and you should not be
allowed to go out of Agra.
How did this suddenly happen?.
Jai Singh, just now...
This is the plan of Empress.
God knows what
is going to happen.
I think your life
can be in danger.
I am not worried about my life.
What will happen to Khurram?.
What will become of
Arjuman and her children?.
It's good you came in time,...
would have gone.
Keep the forces of Kandhar
ready, may be we will have to...
... fight the
royal forces of Agra.
As you say.
Revenge can make the character
of a woman so terrifying.
This, I realized today.
Read it carefully, this is what
could be our situation in future.
No, I had earlier said
that Khurram is a rebel.
Later, I had to repent.
May be this news has
been spread by his enemies.
Emperor may be, what one
hears could be wrong, but...
... what one
sees cannot be wrong.
Ask my loyal friends they have
seen everything with their eyes.
This is correct Dil-E-Elahi.
Prince Khurram,
Shahjehan is for an attack.
- But why is he doing this?.
- To attack Agra.
He wants to take over Agra and
arrest the Empress and Emperor.
Quiet, I do not have the
strength to hear that this...
selfish person, that
thankless of arresting me.
How does he have the courage
to take over the throne as...
... I am still alive.
At once for his arrest,
an artillery unit should go.
You are right Emperor.
But who has the courage
to face Mewar and Deccan?.
Raja Jaisingh, the Mughal empire
is not bereft of brave warriors.
I will appoint Mahabat
Khan to head this campaign.
Empress, you and
Mahabat Khan......
He is my enemy, but not the
enemy of the Mughal empire.
I will forget my personal enmity
and protect the Mughal empire.
Give the order to
the forces to be ready.
Outside Burhanpur, I will face
the challenge of Mahavat Khan.
My dear, do not fight against
the royal forces of the empire.
If there is a fight
between the the world will laugh.
The justice of Jehangir
will be under question.
The brave stories and
valour of prince Khurram will...
... be termed as lies.
Sister Arjuman is right.
Rana Karan Singhji its you.
How come the King of Mewar...
... is in Burhanpur.
As soon as I came to know that
there is going to be a battle...
... between Jehangir and
Khurram I couldn't stop my self.
Prince, for the sake of our
friendship and love which...
... you had, with my dead father
Amar Singh and now with me,...
... please stop this war.
If the swords of the father
and son clash with each other...
the heads of children in all
times, will hang down in shame.
Believe me Rana, I have
not tried to start this war.
My enemies want my throne
my crown, and my life too.
- For which I am going to
fight. - To save your life.
Yes, because my life and
each of mine belongs to somebody.
You come with me Udaipur. For
your life and respect..
... I can sacrifice my life.
This is the oath of a Rajput.
But Karan Singh, Mahabat Khan has
left Agra with the Mughal forces.
He will follow
us into Mewar too.
Mahabat Khan will not have
the courage to step inside the...
... border of Mewar and if
his arrogance makes him reach...
... the doors of Mewar, then
this war will not be between...
... the father and son
but between Mahabat Khan...
... and Karan Singh.
The war will not be fought for
the throne and crown of lndia,...
but for the safety of the
life and respect of a brother.
Come on prince. The whole of
Mewar is waiting to welcome you.
My dear husband,
please agree to this advice.
May be this is good for us.
'No, please don't touch me.'
'l tell you again and again,
don't touch me.'
'Your beauty is golden,
and your tricks.'
'Your eyes are a
treasure of color, I like them.'
'My brother is strong,
my beloved is strong.'
'Swords will rise
if you look at me.'
'Your whole family will mourn
you. You will risk your life.'
The sword of your eyes
have pierced my heart.
Couldn't gaze at you,
such beauty you had.
It is beyond expressions!
My beloved guards the
treasure of my beauty.
May my beloved live just like
the depth of my love.
You are a stranger!
Mahabat Khan has come.
Rana Karan Singh you have given
shelter to the rebel of the...
... Mughal empire..
On behalf of Shehanshah Jehangir
I request you to hand over...
... Sultan Khurram to me.
Sultan Khurram is my brother,
and begum Arjuman is my sister.
I will not under any cost
hand over the husband of...
... my sister to you.
I am reading the royal
order in the name of Khurram.
If my rebel son Khurram
sends both his sons,...
in the service of the emperor,
his misdeeds will be forgiven,...
as I am responsible for
their safety and well being.
This order is not Emperor
Jehangir's but that of Empress.
To take away
innocent children...
from the parents does not
depict Noorjehan wants to take.
Mahabat Khan is the subject
and has to follow his order.
Rana Karan Singh, will the royal
command be adhered to or not.
No. - The emperor who has
become his son's enemy,...
why will he be kind
to his sons children.
He is cutting the roots, so how
can he claim that the branches...
... of the trees will flourish.
You will not get the
children Mahabat Khan.
If you don't listen, the royal
command will be carried out...
... by the use of this sword.
Do not threaten the dynasty of
Rana Sanga and Maharana Pratap.
The heads of the Rajput kings
did not bow down, even in front...
... of the valiant emperor
Akbar, and King Sher Shah.
So today, my head
will not bow down.
I take an oath that I will
get the heads of my children...
cut, and also the heads of
all the children in my kingdom...
but I will see, that the sons
of my sister come to no harm.
You do not understand,
there will be such a fight...
that rivers of
blood will flow here.
Stop there Mahabat Khan.
What Rana Karan has
said is bound to happen.
A Rajput's vow is invincible.
You too have
said blood will flow.
The blood of these valiant
people who have done no harm.
But before the end comes
this disaster will not...
... be allowed to take place.
I will see that
this never takes place.
Mahabat Khan, l
surrender myself to you.
- Sultan! - Arrest him.
Wait.
My brother kept the
dignity of the Rajputs.
He was ready to sacrifice
his life for my children.
In front of my eyes I will
not let my husband be taken away.
Mahabat Khan, take my sons.
I sacrifice my loved ones...
... for the sake of my husband.
Sister, what are you doing?.
What my religion has taught me.
I am obeying
of the holy book.
My sweet princes,
good bye may god bless you.
When you meet Shah
Baba wish him from my side.
Mother!
Empress's greatness
is as strong as ever.
The Mughal dynasty is
still on a strong foundation.
The artillery unit carrying
the royal order encountered...
... success, and the
order was accepted by Shahjehan.
Very good,
Mahabat Khan. Very good!
By achieving this incomparable
deed, you have raised not only...
Our power, but have increased your
status and position in our eyes.
On behalf of my self, the
Emperor, and Mughal empire...
... I congratulate you.
Empress I have brought the two
sons of Shahjehan too, with me.
Let them be brought here. I
am anxiously waiting to see them.
Now Shahjehan, all his life will
not be able to rebel against me.
Come children come to me.
- We will go to Shah Bahadur.
- I want to go to mother.
Your mother is very far now.
and Shah baba is sick.
- What has happened?. - Emperor
Jehangir has passed away.
Zil E Elahi has died.
Emperor is no more now.
Emperor Jehangir is dead.
Emperor
Jehangir has passed away.
O God, what is realizes now.
If only she listens to justice.
She is not a woman
but as hard as stone.
As soon as the
emperor passed away,...
she announced that
Shariyar should become the king.
And that Shahjehan should
be called here and killed.
If Shahjehan is killed, then
with it the Mughal empire will die.
The ill deeds of Noorjehan
and Shariyar will destroy lndia.
Is there anyone here who can
send my message to Shahjehan...
... that his destruction
is being planned here.
Make the security more tight
and put more guards around him.
The archers should be told
that if Asif Khan even looks out...
... of the window or balcony
his eyes. should be removed.
Today lndia is mine.
The crown and throne...
... of lndia is mine.
The earth and sky is mine.
I am Dil e Tomani Jalal e Pana,
Sultan e Jahan, the emperor...
... Saifuddin Shariyar!
Arjuman, sister Arjuman, as
long as the Emperor is alive...
... no one can harm your sons.
- Shahjehan there has
been a disaster. - What!
The emperor has passed away
and Empress has announced...
... that Shariyar
will be the emperor.
My sons, I know
Shariyar will kill my sons.
Be calm and don't lament, or
else the world will say that...
... Arjuman is
weak and a coward.
Shahjehan I will get
twenty thousand forces ready.
Give me your order, and l
will attack Agra, like lightning.
Twenty thousand brave Rajputs
will have to face the Mughal...
... forces, which
are ten times more
They also have five
thousand of Shariyar's men,...
and Mahabat Khan
is there with them.
But we too will fight and
show them our valour and bravery.
Mahabat Khan will like to
serve brave kings like Khurram,...
but will never accept
weak and good for nothing...
... Shariyar as the King.
Shahjehan I Mahabat Khan, is
ready to serve you and have...
come here with
the Moghul forces.
Very good.
Excellent Mahabat Khan.
But what is the proof that
you will be loyal to Shahjehan?.
I have brought
that proof with me.
- Father, father! - My children.
Mother! Mother!
Mahabat Khan you
have touched my heart.
Lets not delay now
The forces are ready.
Success is waiting to
take you into its fold.
India is yours. The
throne and crown is yours.
I have some bad news,
Shahjehan is coming towards...
... Agra with a very big
contingent of the Rajputs.
What guts does he have to
even as long as I am there.
What do you have to say?.
Well, the great poets of
Delhi are busy writing pages...
and pages in
praise of your greatness.
Sir the forces have surrounded
the city, and there is anarchy.
Close the gates to the city.
When I get up I'll crush him.
What else is happening?.
From the treasures of the world
great beauties are being sent for.
Precious jewels
are being sent sir.
- What else?. - Sir
shiploads of liquor...
... are coming
from England and lran.
Here, useless talk of liquor
and jewels is being discussed...
while Shahjehan's
forces are after another.
Empress!
On one hand there
sleeping destiny...
with acts of bravery, the echo
of which is heard in his sword.
While on the other side
you are trying to put...
... your fortunes to
sleep by singing lullabies.
Come to your senses
Shariyar lts no game to get the...
.. throne and crown.
Empress I will achieve the
throne by my valour and go the...
... battlefield and put
victory flags all over.
The person who is in a state
of drunkenness, what kind of...
... victory flags will
he put in the battlefield.
I wish I had not made
this mistake in judging you.
Shariyar I am not angry
with you, but I am angry...
... with myself.
and with my destiny.
Stop it Malika E Alam. I
can't listen to these taunts.
I take an oath on you, that l
will colour Agra red, with...
... the blood of the enemies.
Asif Khan your
fortunes are now with you.
Mahabat Khan has given
his full support to Shahjehan.
The few supporters of
Shariyar too have rebelled and...
... now there is no
one to support Shariyar.
God may delay in giving
justice but he doesn't...
... close his eyes.
Shariyar and his accomplices
should be arrested immediately.
Tomorrow, soon after sunrise
the of the city should be opened.
I will give
Shahjehan a royal welcome.
It is my desire that before l
become the emperor I should...
... make you wear the
crown with my own hands.
Begum congratulations for
being crowned the Empress.
Empress congratulations!
You are my crown!
You too are everything of mine.
If you were not my destiny
then I would not have been...
... anything today.
You have made Shahjehan
by your sacrifices, your...
... dedicated love has
made you different from the...
...the other women of the world
and that is why you are so strong.
That is why comparing you
to Mumtaz, I give you the...
... title of Begum Mumtaz Mahal.
Thank you!
From today I will not
call you Arjuman but will...
... address you as Mumtaz.
The life of Shahjehan, Mumtaz.
The great emperor Shahjehan is
arriving, let everyone stand...
... in respect to the
great emperor, who will now...
... take over the
throne and empire.
Respectfully stand to
welcome the great emperor.
Congratulations to the
great emperor and King.
I want to thank
the Mughal dynasty...
from oblivion and also saved it
from the treachery of Noorjehan.
It was due to the loyalty and
commitment of King Karan Singh...
... and the prime minister Asif
Khan, that I have been able to...
... acquire the
throne and crown.
Hail King Karan Singh!
Before the emperor starts
discussing about his future...
... strategy he wants to
know how have the traitors and...
... rebels been treated.
Practically all the traitors
and rebels have been jailed.
There is only one rebel who
can be punished, by no one...
... else except the
Shahenshah himself.
Who is that?.
The former Malika of
lndia Mehrunissa Noorjehan.
Let her be brought here.
Her crimes should be read out.
I will tell
everyone about them myself.
I got prince Khurram attacked
to get him killed, so that...
Shariyar could get the throne.
I got prince Khurram declared
a rebel and a traitor twice,...
... so that he does not
get the throne and the crown.
I took away both the
children of Shahjehan from him.
So that he doesn't to
rebel against the emperor.
I did what I wanted, and thought
what was right for the empire.
Today the empire is yours.
You too, will do what I did.
This is the tradition of the
emperors and this has never...
... changed, nor will it
ever change in the future.
Begum Noorjehan, you
have on behalf of the late...
... emperor and on behalf
of yourself committed such...
... grave crimes, which,
leave alone human beings,...
... but God too
will never forgive.
In order to have control
on wealth and rule of the...
... empire, you tried to
separate two people who...
... Ioved each other
and even tried to kill them.
Begum Noorjehan that person
is not a human being, either...
... in the eyes of God or
in the eyes of society,...
... who is neither sorry for
her sins or those for which,...
... she will be punished,
by the Almighty.
For my grave sins and crimes
I will be answerable in the...
... the court
of the supreme God.
But, on earth you As an
emperor you have been...
... given the right to give
life, and sentence people...
... to death too.
According to the rules of
the Mughal empire I should be...
... punished
according to the what I deserve.
I was just living for this
day when the power to punish,...
... would be in my hands.
and the power, as a King...
... to make the
destiny of my subjects.
I give you an assurance that l
will not take revenge from you.
I am not afraid of punishment
nor do I want to beg for mercy.
Nor am I ashamed for what I did.
I am surprised that you
are standing at deaths door...
... but you still are not
repenting, nor is your head...
... bowed in repentance.
Here in front of everyone where
you have admitted your crimes...
... I will give you the
most deadly punishments.
So that the
others learn a lesson.
I want to give
begum Noorjehan...
I agree that the crimes of
Begum Noorjehan are very serious.
At this moment she is standing
of the emperor as a criminal.
The emperor has the right to
give any punishment he wants.
Before you pronounce the
punishment, just think once...
... that in front of you is
not just a criminal, but...
... in front of a son,
his mother is standing.
While she was swaying
with power and position...
..your mother had forgotten her
duty, and now that you have...
..the throne and the power with
you as her son, forget your duty too.
I am so pleased with you, Mumtaz
You have reminded me about...
.. my duty and saved me from a
grave mistake I was going to make.
I will be ever grateful to you.
Mother, you were once the
Empress of lndia and today...
... too you are the Empress.
Please bless me that I am
able to look after the kingdom...
... as you would
have wanted me to.
Khurram I bless you!
I congratulate that
mother who gave you birth.
I congratulate that great
lady who has become a part of you.
I have always thought of
you as not my own, and...
... did injustice with you.
But, the respect that you
have given me, I had not ever...
... dreamt that you would.
The empire and rule of
lndia is now in your hands.
My rule had ended that day
itself when my husband and...
... emperor had passed away.
Now give me permission that
the last few days of my life...
... I spend at the
tomb of my husband.
This is my last wish.
The wish of Malika
Alam should be fulfilled.
As you say, your majesty!
So in this manner
many many years passed.
Suddenly in the life of the
Shehanshah who loved his...
... wife so much,
came a big storm.
A storm is coming!
O God, please have
mercy on my Mumtaz.
Emperor, if God wants
there will be good wishes and...
... congratulations all around.
There will be sounds
of happiness all around.
Congratulations Emperor, you
have got a beautiful daughter!
Congratulations!
God, thank you a thousand times!
Let there be celebrations
all around and the poor...
... should be given gifts.
What happened?.
Emperor, Empress is in
a very serious condition.
Mumtaz, I have come.
The time has come for me to go.
What are you saying, you
had promised to stay with...
... me all my life.
Don't leave me in the
middle of nowhere like this.
I will not let you go.
I will never let you go.
A shining moon, on the
shore of the river Jamuna, the...
... whole
atmosphere is so beautiful.
Prince, when I die
please make my tomb here.
You will make it won't you?.
Do not talk about dying!
I will die without you.
You will make it, won't you?.
I'll make a palace and I take
an oath on God you'll stay there.
You will see so much happiness
and you will see the river...
... flowing by, Mumtaz.
Open your eyes!
Mumtaz, open your eyes!
I will not let you go, Mumtaz!
Mumtaz Mahal has died
many days ago, while Emperor...
... has closed himself in
the Akbari palace for days now.
He doesn't meet anyone, nor
does he eat or drink anything.
God knows what is
happening with him.
- Who is there?. -
Prime minister, Asif Khan!
Go away! The door will not open.
Who is it?.
I am the unfortunate father
of the Arjuman Banoo who...
... is in heaven now.
Let the door be opened!
- Emperor! - What's the matter?.
What is the matter?.
Why are you so frightened?.
Have you forgotten me?.
Or is it that after Mumtaz
friends are no longer friends?.
After Mumtaz has my
glory and respect too gone.
May the emperor
have a long life!
Please forgive your subjects!
But Dil-E-Alahi, look at your face!
My face! What has
happened to my face?.
I am very happy.
I have gone white because
it is a symbol of my mourning.
A symbol of shock.
Mumtaz, I couldn't die in
sorrow for you but I know...
... that I have traversed
hundred years ahead in life.
Why did my funeral
not go along with yours?.
Emperor, be calm and
have patience otherwise...
... the empire will be lost.
When my life has got lost,
then who is scared of the...
... empire going away?.
Dil-E-Elahi have patience.
The traveler has gone...
... forever to that
destination from where...
... she will never come back.
Those who leave the world
and go, do not come back.
Why don't they come back?.
The promise that you have
made will have to be fulfilled.'
May the world stop
you or may God stop you.'
You will have to come.'
The whole world
tells me that no one..
..comes from the
land of the dead.'
Let the world see the
glory of loyalty today.'
You will have to come.'
The promise that you made,
you will have to fulfill it.'
I agree that we will
have to give up my life.'
understand this,
whenever you call..
..'me I will have to come.'
The promise that I have made,
I will have to fulfill it.'
I have been coming,
and I will continue coming.'
I will continue
completing the rituals of love.'
My loyal lover,
if you call me..'
..There is no other way,
I will have to come.'
You have to come Mumtaz.
You have kept your promise.
You have proved
that our love is eternal.
We can die but even then we
cannot be away from each other.
My dear, what is this
condition you have made of yours?.
I am burning deeply in my
sorrow, of being away from you.
I have become a heap
of ashes in your sorrow.
What sorrow! What separation!
I am dead for the world.
But, I am still alive for you.
See I am here. The same
shining moon, the same...
shore of the Yamuna river but
my dear, you are not the same.
- You have forgotten your
promise. - Which promise?.
The memory of our love.
The promise of our love.
My dear, till that palace
is not made I will be restless.
Mumtaz in your sorrow,
I forgot everything.
I forgot myself.
I forgot my promise.
I promise I will fulfill it.
Now, till I don't fulfill it l...
... will not rest, fulfilling
it will be the goal of my life.
It will be the
goal of my life Mumtaz.
Was it a Dream,
was all this a dream.
No she had come here.
My Mumtaz did come here.
She was sitting here with me.
Her voice is still
echoing in my ears.
The memory of love.
A palace of love.
Yes, that palace
will definitely be made.
That palace will be made Mumtaz!
Emperor the artisan who makes
this palace will see that it...
... conforms with the
greatness of Empress in every way.
The palace will be adorned with
jewels and domes reaching the sky.
Diamonds will sparkle from it.
I do not want a palace which is
adorned with jewels and diamonds.
I want a palace in which my
emotions, and not my wealth...
... is depicted. I want
my love to be seen in that.
Why are you quiet?. The
Shah of lran has praised...
... your work a lot, you
too give your suggestions.
Dil-E-Elahi, I am
Shirazi a poor artisan...
and I cannot think
about diamonds and jewels.
The design which I have
in mind is very simple and...
... different from the rest.
This is what I want, l
want the Taj to be different...
from the rest and the
most unusual of the lot.
That palace will
be carved of marble.
Yes! Which will
have such fragrance!
That will in moonlit nights
make the hearts of lovers yearn.
In which, beauty
will speak for itself.
When that palace gets
ready then in the whole world...
... the light of
love will spread.
Shirazi, you are not an
artisan but a magician.
You have said, what I have
felt you have stolen my dreams.
I and Mumtaz had together
seen this dream of such a palace...
... near the
shore of the Yamuna.
Go Shirazi, and as soon
as possible make this palace!
Mumtaz is
restless desperate for it.
It is a memory of our love.
The palace of love.
The shore of the Yamuna and
this loneliness around it,...
... my beloved husband.
Mumtaz is thinking of me. She
is calling out to me for years.
I will have to go.
I want to see the Taj Mahal.
Take me to Mumtaz!
As you say, Lord!
Take me to her! Take me to her!
Beautiful!
The shore of Yamuna!
The foundation of love!
The palace of love!
The goal of my life is over.
I feel lonely
without you, Mumtaz.
The promise that you have
done, you will have to fulfill it.'
May the world stop you,
or may God himself stop you.'
It is agreed that I will
have to give up my life.'
Understand this, whenever
you call, I will have to come.'
My story is your legend. It
will remembered by the world.'
What accusation
and what punishment??'
I will have to come.'
The promise that we have made,
we will have to fulfill it.'
May the world stop us,
or may God himself stop us.'